Amira Essam Awad Holden

5026 3rd Ave. S., Minneapolis, MN 55419 Portfolio: https://amiracat.github.io/portfolio/ LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/amiraholden/ 612-221-2185

GitHub: https://github.com/amiracat

amiraholden@gmail.com

A problem-solver with 10 years of experience working in Content Management and Strategy, Amira (she/her) is diving further into the web dev stack to complement her front-end skills and gain back-end chops. She is passionate about web accessibility and will graduate from coding bootcamp in October 2021.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

HTML

CSS, Bootstrap, Bulma

JavaScript

JQuery

Node.is

Front-end development

Express

❖ MySQL

Handlebars.js

Debugging

UI/UX

❖ AEM, WordPress

EXPERIENCE

Coding projects

- What Should I Watch? Movie and drink recommender tool built using JQuery, Bulma, 2 APIs: https://amiracat.github.io/what-should-i-watch/
- ❖ Weather Dashboard pulls forecast for any input city and saves the data. Uses Bootstrap, JavaScript, API, localStorage: https://amiracat.github.io/weather-dashboard/
- ❖ Online trivia game using Express session and cookies, and MySQL, Node, Handlebars, Green Sock animation deployed on Heroku: https://young-harbor-83683.herokuapp.com/

UXDesign Content Strategist

U.S. Bank (June 2019 – March 2021)

- Champion accessibility (A11y) by testing and optimizing PDFs, fixing authorable defects, creating defect-free HTML webpages and consulting with the A11y team on training and ongoing projects. Also test components and pages for functional and A11y defects using Deque automated tools.
- Build pages and publish content & assets using Adobe Experience Manager. Help plan and test new components. Optimize content to ensure brand and web style compliance.
- Partner with A11y, marketing, developers, designers, SEO and SiteCat tagging teams to ensure a top-quality digital experience for all users. U.S. Bank Spot Award winner for volunteer effort.
- Act in a leadership capacity by creating an Authoring Community of Practice (COP) team to share best practices, by organizing and leading COP meetings and by leading content strategy for several BAU (business as usual) dotcom projects. Also mentor co-workers.
- Write content for internal SharePoint sites, write error messaging, create documentation.

Member of Agile journey team, using Jira to log stories, defects and time.

AEM Content Author

U.S. Bank, contractor through Matrix (January 2019 – June 2019)

- Built, updated and published pages, fragments and assets using AEM to ensure a consistent experience on usbank.com.
- Partnered with A11y, marketing, developers, designers, SEO and SiteCat tagging teams to ensure a top-quality digital experience for all users.
- Led content strategy on promotional projects.

Digital Content Management Specialist

Hanley Wood Marketing (September 2011 – January 2019)

- Tech lead and senior CMS expert on phase of website migration to Adobe Experience Manager.
- Created, tested and maintained digital content within content management systems including AEM,
 TeamSite and WordPress.
- Collaborated with editorial and design staff to ensure content met clients' expectations.
- Proofed content and ensured writing, SEO and web style guidelines were adhered to.
- Recommended specific CMS template layouts based on client and project needs.
- Built and edited HTML emails.

Copy Editor/News Editor

Internet Broadcasting (August 2007 – August 2011)

- Edited with speed and accuracy for more than 60 TV stations' websites nationwide.
- Led client consultations, rewrote headlines using SEO strategies and offered writing tips to editors.
- Created and posted news & images using the company's CMS.

EDUCATION

University of Minnesota

Bachelor of Arts

• Double major: Journalism, Middle Eastern Studies

OTHER EXPERIENCE

- QA: testing on multiple devices, documentation
- HTML email building and mass email marketing: Salesforce, Constant Contact
- Copy editing: AP style, brand guidelines, in-house style; attention to detail and consistency
- SEO: writing, strategy, implementation
- Social media: writing, strategy, community management
- Excellent verbal and written communicator. Great problem-solving and organizational skills.